Hey.
It's going
to be okay.
Just tell me we're
doing the right thing.
No, sweetheart,
I know you want to fix this.
It's what you do.
But we've tried.
All right? We've been trying
and look where it's gotten us.
And I think the space
is gonna be good for him.
For all of us.
Besides, it's a good school.
He'll be home by
the end of the summer.
Yeah.
I'll be okay.
I promise.
Love you.
Love you, too.
- Call me.
- Will do.
I love you.
Wow.
Well done, Stephen.
Amazing!
Oh, stop, Mom!
What's that? What's that?
Huh? Oh!
One, two, three!
- Nice.
- Yeah!
He's pretty dead.
He's very dead.
Today my son
has become a man.
Because of that...
I know you think we're probably
doing this to punish you,
but we're not.
All right?
Your mother and I
want the best for you.
You have no idea
what she wants.
I don't know why
you're doing this.
I'm not the one
that got expelled, pal.
Well, she doesn't
want me gone. It's you.
That's not true,
Stephen.
Yes, it is.
You're sending me away.
It's not true,
Stephen.
Your mother and I had
a long conversation...
About what?
We need a break, Stephen!
I don't want a break!
All right?
Both of us, okay?
Shut up! I hate you!
Just calm down. Calm down!
No, don't touch me!
Don't touch me!
You just calm down!
Calm down!
Wakey, wakey.
Rise and shine.
You ready for your workout?
Open.
...significant snowfall likely
across all of New England,
when all is said and done.
So, as the storm approaches,
you'll want to make sure you take
the necessary precautions here
and plan on some very heavy snow
in your area for much of...
It's your turn.
How about a quick try?
Great job.
Hey.
So I'd like
to continue working with him
for another
couple weeks.
It's not my decision.
They're moving him
to Boston.
Some group home
for deaf kids.
But we're making
progress.
These things take time.
He's a great kid,
we can...
He broke another
kid's arm last week.
He can't stay
at Sweetser.
I'm really sorry.
We're leaving.
Joan!
Wait a second.
I guess it was like a...
I guess it was like certificates
for all the smart people,
so basically I have nothing.
I... I did not...
I want you
to have these.
Keep warm, okay?
Well, you can't take care of
every kid in Maine, Mary.
I know.
Um...
No one would
judge you for needing help.
Thanks.
Hi, Dr. Wilson.
How are you?
How's it all going?
Long day.
Long week.
Well, Stephen really keeps you
on your toes, doesn't he?
How's he doing?
I received the papers.
I'm moving him to Covington.
Physically, I can manage.
Just about,
but it's not him.
It's just a body that I feed,
and wash, and clothe.
I lost him that day
I lost Richard in the car.
Mary, being a psychologist doesn't
make you a perfect parent.
There's no such thing.
You did what you
thought was right.
I sent him away.
I sent my son away
and now he's gone.
Mama's gonna
buy you a mockingbird
And if that
mockingbird don't sing
Mama's gonna buy you
A diamond ring
911, what's your emergency?
Hello?
Yes, this is Mary Portman
from 28 Delphi Lane.
I think there is
an intruder in my house.
Okay, stay on the line.
Mrs. Portman,
are you inside the house?
Can you hear me?
Mrs. Portman, are you still there?
Hello?
I'm sorry, my mistake.
It's just a raccoon.
Here you go.
This will warm you up.
You okay?
Oh. Hold on. Hello?
Joan, hi.
Thanks for calling back.
I'm sorry,
I know it's late.
How did he even get here?
It's 15 degrees out.
I know it's not,
but please, Joan.
I can help him.
He could just stay here.
Hang on a second.
Is that necessary?
What? Let me...
Give it a chance, okay?
I can help him.
What good could it do
to involve the police?
I'll take that chance. He's nine years old,
for God's sake, Joan, please!
Can you just let him...
Joan, I'll call you back.
Tom!
Jesus.
You sure I can't get you another
before you head back out, Joe?
Thanks, Mary.
I'm gonna press on,
start going door
to door.
A young kid out alone won't survive
long in these temperatures.
...though on
their company website
have much higher sales numbers
and conversion rates.
I just feel so helpless.
Yeah, I...
I've been out all afternoon
looking for him myself.
Oh, God, Joan.
I can't stand to think of him
out there on his own.
Yeah, okay, um...
Well, just promise me you'll call
as soon as you hear anything.
Okay.
Great.
Okay. Bye.
Tom!
Mary?
Hon?
Didn't you hear me?
I was worried.
What are you doing in here?
I, uh... I was just...
I thought I'd make up
Stephen's bed in case...
In case Tom came back.
Oh.
What time is it?
It's late.
Aaron Hart is waiting
for you in the office.
I mean, the kid's been
bouncing around foster homes
for, like, half his life,
but no one gave a shit then.
And now suddenly
the whole town's
decided it's
time to give a shit.
Do you know how
many children run away
or go missing every year in
the United States alone?
I don't know.
Don't you see how
fucked up that is?
Besides, the kid's dead.
Everyone knows it.
Okay, Aaron, that's about
all we have time for today.
Whatever, sure.
Thanks a lot.
Is your dad
coming to get you?
Uh-huh.
Teenagers,
huh?
How's it going?
Does he hate me
more or less
than he hates the rest
of the world today?
No, he's just having a rough time
with the move and the divorce.
Sometimes it's hard to remember
he was just a cute little kid
who liked to throw a ball around
with his dad a few years ago.
He's so angry
all the time.
He'll get through it.
It's just
a difficult age.
You hear about
this storm coming in?
Yeah.
If it turns into
an ice storm,
we could be without power for
at least a couple of days.
Mmm.
You probably shouldn't
be up here all alone.
Aaron and I are
thinking of moving into
one of the hotels in
town to ride it out.
Uh...
If we do, maybe I could
take you for dinner.
I'll be fine.
We'll be fine.
My son, he's sick,
so I can't really move him.
Oh. I'm sorry
to hear that.
I didn't even know you had a son.
How old is he?
He's 18. Stephen's 18.
He's my stepson.
I didn't know that...
My husband
passed away, actually,
so it's just
Stephen and me now.
Well, maybe the four of us
can get dinner one day.
You know, you, me
and our angry teenagers.
Look, it's not really
appropriate.
Aaron's my patient,
so...
And he's waiting
for you in the car.
Sure, okay.
Uh, um...
Well, listen, thanks.
Sorry, I just...
I hope your son
feels better.
Thanks.
Shit.
Oh, shit.
It's okay.
I feel like I'm
losing my mind.
Mary, calm down.
Look, listen to what
you're saying.
I was there. It was real.
You're a rational adult.
There's no such things as ghosts,
and you know that.
Oh, God.
I think that you experienced
something known as parasomnia.
A sleep disorder that
can trigger night terrors.
I... But I saw him.
I saw Tom.
Everybody's been
saying he's dead,
and I kept wanting it not
to be true, but it must be.
I think that with the amount
of stress you're under
and the existence
of disturbed sleep already,
it makes complete sense.
And frankly,
you know, the fact that
you saw the runaway boy
also tracks.
You know, you've been
looking for him,
you're worried about him.
Does not mean he's dead,
let alone haunting you.
Do you think that the sound
of the child's footsteps
in your dream could be a
reminder of the child that
you might think
you've actually lost?
You know, of the son that used
to come into your room at night
when he was scared.
Do you think that
that voiceless child
in your dream
could be Stephen...
...as much as it's Tom?
Long before the accident,
I remember you telling me that
you were feeling
like you were losing Stephen.
That you were
losing your little boy.
Do you remember that?
Mmm-hmm.
I had been through so much.
Yeah. Well,
tell me about that Stephen.
You know,
Stephen before the accident.
Before the behavioral
problems even.
I never told you this,
but that morning,
he begged me not
to send him away.
Go on.
Stephen always
blamed Richard.
But I was the one
who found the school.
I just didn't know how to be
his therapist and his mother.
Mary?
Look, the nightmare
about Tom
may be about Stephen,
but that's because
everything's about Stephen.
Look, I'd like to talk to you
about prescribing something
to regulate your sleep, okay?
So I'm gonna need
some blood work.
In the meantime,
take care of yourself.
Thanks.
...starts to attack humans
when we're not
their natural prey.
And can scientists find a way
to prevent these tragic events?
Hi. Sorry, I was,
uh... Come in.
This shark is the most
charismatic fish in the ocean.
White sharks can weigh in
excess of 4 or 5,000 pounds.
Get in excess of 20 feet long.
So, that's a very big fish.
We know that these
sharks can live...
So, what are we doing for
this young man today, then?
Actually, it's for me.
I just need some
blood work done.
What's wrong with you?
Nothing, I'm fine.
Then why haven't you taken
yourself to the doctor?
I don't like to
leave him alone.
I try not to leave
the house too much.
Handsome boy.
He's got your eyes.
He's not...
Thank you.
You take care of
him on your own?
Mmm-hmm.
Hmm.
He looks good.
Strong.
You must be doing
something right.
Blood pressure is too high
for a woman your age.
Could we just, um...
None of my beeswax.
I get it.
You just wait.
The doctor will tell you the same
thing when he gets the results.
So, when are
you taking Stephen in?
End of the month.
Dr. Wilson says I need to start
practicing leaving the nest.
I'm not really sure
this counts.
I saw Doug Hart
in town yesterday.
Oh, my God,
I was so rude to him.
Funny.
He thought
he'd offended you.
You should call him.
Ask him out.
Maybe I should call
him just to apologize.
Yeah, to apologize.
I felt like such
an ass the other day.
I had no idea.
Lucy explained
everything to me.
Oh, of course
she did.
That must have been hard,
taking care of him by yourself.
She told you
about that, too?
And yes, Stephen...
I'm moving him
to a care home.
Oh, I'm sorry, I had no idea.
She didn't tell me that.
I thought...
I'm sorry. I...
You know, I...
This is hard. I haven't...
I haven't done this
in a while.
Were you guys close
before the accident?
Very.
He was five when Richard
and I got married.
He was closer to
me than his dad.
But then he hit puberty,
and it was like
I had a stranger in the house.
Yeah, Aaron, too.
I'm just like,
he's a completely
different species.
Aaron is a good kid.
Well, his teachers
disagree.
I had a meeting with the
principal last week.
Principal Hastings?
He's the worst!
So, Stephen
went there, too.
Until he was expelled.
No! What for?
Mmm, the whole thing was totally
blown out of proportion.
There were some kids,
and they were messing around in the pool.
And I guess they were
just teasing Stephen.
One day he retaliated,
but no one got hurt.
After his mom died,
he was dealing with a lot of grief.
And by the time he was a teenager,
he barely spoke to anyone
except me,
and then it was, you know...
I feel like Aaron
talks to everyone but me.
He just completely
shuts me out.
Hmm.
Well, I guess I should
let you two get to bed.
It's getting late.
Stephen?
I told you, something's going on,
and it's not just in my head.
Mary, take a deep breath
and think about
what you're saying.
Please just listen to me.
I thought it was a dream,
but it wasn't.
I was awake and...
Well, sleep parasomnia...
It's not fucking
sleep parasomnia, okay?
Please, you have
to believe me.
And listen to what you're saying.
You're talking about ghosts!
This isn't you.
For God's sake, don't you think
I know how this sounds?
Something is happening.
I can prove it.
Stephen, he has scratches
on his face.
You are sleep deprived.
You're confused.
You're struggling
to make sense of everything
and latching onto
irrational explanations.
Look, maybe you scratched him
yourself by accident.
What?
Oh, God.
I don't know what's worse.
Either this really is happening,
or I'm losing my mind.
I keep hearing
these weird noises
in the walls and
under the floor.
Mary, I am here to help.
Listen, I'm gonna rush the lab
for your blood work,
and then I think
we should get you
straight onto
an anti-depressant.
I'll talk to you in
a few hours, okay?
Okay.
Now, to some breaking news
concerning the young deaf boy
reported missing several days ago
by Social Services.
Within the past hour,
a boy fitting the description
of 9-year-old Tom Patterson
has been spotted in a park
in Hawthorne, Florida.
Acting on a call
from a local resident,
Hawthorne police are now conducting
a wide search of the area.
They speculate he may have
traveled by Greyhound bus,
but as yet are
still to determine
his exact whereabouts.
We'll be back after
the break with more
on the winter
storm heading our way.
Only me!
Hey!
Okay, I know you said that you
didn't need anything, but...
It's hardly my
first rodeo, Luce.
Um... Sure you don't want
to stay with us tonight?
No, we're fine.
For a moment there,
I thought I was...
Are you okay?
Yeah, it's nothing.
I just haven't been
sleeping that well.
Um, sure you have
everything?
Lanterns? Blankets?
Enough wood?
Yes, thank you.
Okay, take care,
all right?
Yeah, you, too.
Yeah. Bye.
Bye.
Lanterns...
Oh, God...
It's just me.
You scared me.
Sorry to barge in.
I tried knocking, but no one answered.
I didn't hear your car.
Yeah, that plow just came.
Your drive's blocked.
I had to park down
the road and walk in.
Oh. Okay.
I just came to say thank you for
last night and see if you're okay.
Aaron and I did end up getting a
suite down at the Holiday Inn,
so, you're sure you guys
don't want to come with us?
No, that's kind of you.
We've weathered worse.
I had a great time
last night.
Me, too.
Um...
I can't tell you what a
relief it is they found Tom.
You know,
the runaway kid.
Yeah, yeah, Florida.
That turned out to
be a false alarm.
You didn't hear?
No.
I mean, I'm sure
he's gonna turn up.
They'll probably
find him two towns over.
...a little bit as you head
further up to the north.
No matter how you
look at it though,
we're talking about
a major winter storm...
You okay?
Uh...
I have a lot to do.
You don't mind
letting yourself out.
Sure.
Doug! I'm...
Hi, Dr. Wilson.
Sorry, I was downstairs.
Mary?
Yeah.
I have just gotten your blood
work back from the lab.
Okay.
Frankly, I'm a little disappointed.
What?
If you'd have told me
you were self-medicating,
we could have avoided
a lot of confusion here.
It's no wonder you're having
so many problems,
given the amount of
pills you're taking.
What are you talking about?
Mary, benzodiazepines are not a
class of drugs we mess around with.
I'm
not taking anything.
Aside from the fact that mixing
prescription drugs can be lethal...
Mixing?
I can only assume that you are
taking medication from Stephen,
which not only puts
your health at risk,
but his also.
You're not listening to me.
I don't know what you're talking about.
I haven't taken anything.
I would have happily prescribed
you something to help you sleep.
It would have
been less potent,
but of course
I would have done it.
You've made a mistake,
those are not my results.
I'm sorry, I really
can't talk right now.
I'm gonna have
to call you back.
Mary.
Mary!
Mary? Mary?
The number
you are trying to call
is not reachable.
Stephen. Stephen...
No! Stop!
Hush little baby
Don't say a word
Mama's gonna
buy you a mockingbird
And if that mockingbird
Mama's gonna
buy you a...
It's okay, it's okay. It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
Hey.
It's okay. I'm here.
No, no, no,
no, no, no! No!
It's okay.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Look. Look at me.
It's your son, Stephen.
It's okay.
I'm gonna take this off.
Okay.
I'm sorry. Okay.
Hush, no! Shh!
Don't scream!
It's okay.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
What's happening?
Please.
I'm taking care of you,
just like you
take care of me.
Am I dreaming?
No.
Not anymore.
I don't understand.
Is... And...
When I woke up
in the hospital,
a week after
the accident,
you were by my side,
waiting on my every need.
But you didn't move.
You didn't speak.
No.
And you all
assumed I couldn't.
I just didn't
want it to end.
And the longer I did nothing,
the easier it got.
The doctors
kept telling you
how little is
known about the brain.
I couldn't understand.
Your scans
kept improving.
Your reflexes
were normal.
You saw what
you wanted to see.
These last few months,
we've been so happy together.
Just you and me,
until he came here.
Tom.
I couldn't let him go.
He'd seen me.
You killed him.
I'm your son!
I'm your son.
Why did you always
pick them over me?
I won't compete anymore.
Hey, no, no.
It's okay. Shh.
Hey, look, hey,
hey, hey, hey.
It's okay.
He's not a ghost.
He's downstairs.
I was gonna deal with him,
but he climbed into the crawlspace.
That was him in my room.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, I thought
it was all over.
But I underestimated these.
He's alive.
I blocked him in.
I was waiting
for him to starve.
That sound of him.
That sound of him
scratching around in the dark.
You know, one in your tea used
to put you down all night.
I had to up the dosage
since he's been here.
Hey, come here,
come here.
Open your mouth.
Please.
Open.
No, no...
Ow!
Stop it! Stop it!
Stop it!
Swallow.
Good girl.
When you wake up,
he'll be gone.
We can go back
to normal.
Just you and me.
I promise.
Hello?
No! No,
do not put me on hold again.
I need you to send someone out
to see Mary Portman.
At 28 Delphi Lane.
No. She...
No, she has not
been in an accident.
I think she's being drugged.
You have
reached your destination.
What?
Shit.
Oh, God...
Shut up!
I thought you'd be happy.
Now you don't
have to send me away.
I just want to
help you, Stephen.
You were in
a terrible accident.
You're not well.
I heard you
last night.
You're trying to
send me away again.
Because of him!
No, no, it's not
because of him.
You gave him my room.
You're replacing me!
No one could ever
replace you.
I promise.
Please, just put
the ax down,
and we can talk
about this.
I can fix this.
We can go back
to how it was.
And I can get you
some help, okay?
Please, just put
the ax down.
It's not loaded.
I'm doing this for us!
Are you okay?
I'm gonna get you
out of here.
No!
Run!
Stephen, please, stop!
Stop it! Stop it!
You're ruining everything.
Calm down.
I am trying to fix
your mess.
Stephen,
this isn't you.
Shut up. Just shut up.
You don't know me.
You're a good boy, Stephen.
No.
It was just
the accident.
It wasn't an accident!
I didn't care if I died
as long as he did.
You're what I... You...
You were sending
me away.
I had to stop him.
I couldn't let him
take me away from you.
Don't touch me.
I would rather die
than be away from you.
Shh...
We don't need
anyone else.
Oh, God. Tom!
No!
Oh, God. Where are you?
Oh, Tom.
Tom, come.
Come down. Come.
Come with me. Quick!
Hush little baby
Don't say a word
Mama's gonna
buy you a mockingbird
And if that
mockingbird won't sing
Mary?
It's Dr. Wilson, are you...
Are you okay?
Mary?
Anybody home?
Everybody okay?
I just thought we'd, uh,
have a little chat
before the police get here.
Oh, God.
I don't really think
that we have time for...
For games right now, do we?
Stephen, it's Dr. Wilson.
Stephen?
You told her
to get rid of me.
But she loves me.
And no one is
gonna keep us apart.
Tom.
It's okay, he's gone.
It's okay.
Here. Put this on.
He's coming.
Oh, God.
You stay here.
I'm coming back for you.
Oh, God, Doug!
Quick, come with me.
Wait...
Wait here. Wait.
Dr. Wilson...
I'm sorry.
It's okay. I'm gonna
get you out of here.
He was here...
The whole time.
I'm so sorry.
In Stephen's mind...
Don't challenge
his delusions.
You understand?
Don't let him see the boy.
It's you he wants, only you.
Enter his delusions...
It's okay, I get you.
No. Get the boy out.
Oh, God!
Oh, God.
Stay here.
It's okay.
No!
Stop! Stop! Please!
No, stop it!
No, listen to me.
Stop. Listen to me.
No! No!
Calm down, calm down.
You were right, okay?
I was focused
on my patients,
when I should have been
thinking about you.
No! No, too late!
Wait! Stop!
I didn't know.
I didn't understand
that you were doing it for us.
I didn't know.
So that we could be together.
No. You liar!
You're helping him.
No, I got rid of him.
No.
I did! He's gone now.
It's just you and me,
I promise!
This is our house.
No.
You were right.
He shouldn't be here.
I was confused.
I thought I'd lost you.
But now you're here.
How could I ever replace you?
I love you, Stephen.
This is where you belong.
You!
Oh, God.
Tom.
There's no way down
from there. Quick!
I got you.
That's it.
Okay, let's go.
Let's go. Quick.
Let's go.
Tom!
Run, Tom!
Go!
Stephen, no!
Please!
Please, no.
Move.
No!
Tom! Tom!
I got you. I got you.
I got...
Are you ready to do this?
Yup, I am.
We both are.
The papers will
be waiting for you.
Thanks, Joan.
He's a lucky kid.
Can I see?
It's good.
You want a dog?
Maybe.
It's gonna be good.
And if
that mockingbird don't sing
Mama's gonna buy
you a diamond ring
Hush, little baby,
don't say a word
Mama's gonna buy
you a mockingbird